Jacob Amador 93jcbo@gmail.com

713-598-9210 www.93jcbo.com

Summary

A UX Designer with the skills of a Front-End Developer specializing in mobilefirst responsive design. I believe in user centered design and putting function over flash. I have strong opinions on design but I will always back them up with user research or empirical data.

Skills

UX Design, Responsive Web Design, Mobile First Design, Wireframing, Mockups, Cross Browser Testing, Photoshop CS6, Typography, HTML5, CSS3, Twitter Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, AngularJS, JSON

Education

Rice University, 2015

BA in Cognitive Science with concentration in Human-Computer Interaction Relevant Courses: Human Computer Interaction, Methods of Human Computer Interaction, Non-Traditional Interfaces, Engineering Psychology

Experience

Front-End Developer

First Creative

NOV 2013 - PRESENT

- Convert site mockups to live HTML, CSS, and JavaScript from scratch.
- Consistently produce designs and graphics in Photoshop that impress clients.
- Update client site structure and stylesheets for seamless responsive design.
- Contribute to design decisions by applying modern UX principles.

Front-End Developer

93jcbo.com (Personal Project)

NOV 2014 - JAN 2015

- Built portfolio site using HTML5, CSS3, AngularJS and JSON.
- Optimized site for all screens with responsive web design using Bootstrap.
- Used low-fidelity wireframes to reach a minimalist, function-focused design.

Full Stack Developer

CulturalsBoss (Personal Project)

MAY 2013 - SEP 2013

- Used Photoshop to create mockups for all website pages.
- Converted mockups to live HTML, CSS, and PHP code.
- Designed relational databases in MySQL to populate inner website pages.